A register of the Aleksandr Il'ich Ginzburg Papers, 1921-2007
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1950s-2002; 3 boxes (Box 14-16)
  - Friends and public figures, 1950s-1995 and undated (Envelope 15: 1-8, 16: 1-6)
    - 43 prints of Larisa Bogoraz, Viktor Dziadko, Nina Eroshenko, Oleg Fedorov, Vadim Gaenko, Nina, IUriĬ Gastev, Lidiia Iofe, Elizaveta Iofe, Veniamin Iofe, SergeĬ Khakhaev, Mark and AlekseĬ Kharitonov, Tat'iana and SergeĬ Khodorovich, Alla Khromova, Tat'iana Khromova (Bakhmina), AndreĬ KistiakovskiĬ, IUliĬ Kim, Liudmila Klimakova, Igor' and Vera Kogan, Liudmila Kovaleva, AndreĬ Krasulin, Vera Lashkova, Aleksandr Lavut, Flora Litvinova, SergeĬ Moshkov, Irina Orlova, Boris Pakel'chik, Gulia Romanova, Irina Ronkina, Vladimir Sirotin, ValeriĬ Smolkin, Rina Smolkina, Viktor Timachev, Elizaveta Tsitovskaia, Sara Tverdokhlebova, Yuri Yarim-Agaev, Boris Zelikson, Leonid Ziman, and others, 1970s-1980s. (Envelope 15: 8)
    - 38 prints of Vladimir BukovskiĬ, Igor' Golomshtok, Sof'ia Kalistratova, Viktor Kalnyn'sh, Liudmila Kovaleva, Kronid LiubarskiĬ, Mikhail Makarenko, SergeĬ Men'shutin, Maria Rozanova (Siniavski), AndreĬ Sakharov, Feliks Serebrov, DmitriĬ ShakhovskoĬ, Leonid Shcharansky, Vladimir Shelkov, IUriĬ Shikhanovich, Boris Shragin, AndreĬ SiniavskiĬ, Mariia Slonim, ValeriĬ Smolkin and his family, Petr Starchik, Saida Starchik, Gabriel' Superfin, Valentin Turchin, M. Zinov'eva, Aleksandr Zinov'ev, and others and participants of the Sakharov Russian Institute in Germany, Late 1970s-1982. (Envelope 16: 1)
    - 31 prints of DmitriĬ Bobyshev, Vladimir BukovskiĬ, IUliĬ and Aleksandr Daniel', Viktor Dziadko, Viktor Erofeev, Viktor FaĬnberg, Natal'ia Fedorova, EvgeniĬ Gabovich, IUriĬ Galanskov, Aleksandr Galich, IUriĬ Gastev, SergeĬ Genkin, Natal'ia Gorbanevskaia with her sons, Petr and Zinaida Grigorenko and their sons, Leonid Pliushch, Ekaterina Velikanova, V. Zhivov, and others, 1970s-1980s and 1998. (Envelope 16: 2)
    - 20 prints, of Valentina Kropivnitskaia, Aleksandr and Oskar Rabin, Lev Regel'son, Il'ia Rips, Vladimir Riabokon', ValeriĬ Ronkin, Irina Ronkina, Vladimir Sirotinin, Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn and his sons, and others, 1970s-1993. (Envelope 16: 3)
    - 14 prints of ParuĬr AĬrikian, AndreĬ and Giuzel' Amal'rik (contains letter on the back), cultural and social events in the Montgeron Russian Center, 1976-1980s and undated. (Envelope 16: 4)
    - 17 prints of a press-conference at home of AndreĬ Sakharov and Elena Bonner re trials of Ginzburg, Shcharansky, and Piatkus; and departure of Liudmila, Arina, Aleksandr (son), and AlekseĬ Ginzburg from the USSR, 1978 July; 1 February 1980. (Envelope 16: 5)
    - 5 slides of Ginzburgs' friends, Early 1980s. (Envelope 16: 6)
- Sound and video recordings, 1970s-1990s; undated; 10 boxes and three folders (Box 17-27; 11: 9-11;)
  Includes three groups: compact audio cassettes; uncensored recordings of famous Soviet/Russian singers and poets; and video cassettes and four notebooks with detailed descriptions of content of the compact audio cassettes in the first group.
  First group of audio cassettes and video cassettes arranged by number assigned by Arina Ginzburg; uncensored recordings arranged alphabetically by personal name.
  - Four notebooks with detailed descriptions of the content of each recording, except for no. 31, compiled by Arina Ginzburg, undated (Folder 11: 9-11)
  - Sound recordings, 1978 and 1980s-1990s. (Tape 17-19)
    Includes 126 compact sound cassettes with radio programs, telephone conversations, and Ginzburg's McCoff lectures; and four unnumbered cassettes.
    Cassettes nos. 26, 30, 35, and 46 were not delivered
    - IUliĬ Daniel'; reading Knut Skujenieks poetry, 1978-1979. (Tape 17)
      Ginzburg and Viktor Kalnyn'sh also took part in this recording made in camp
      The tape is unnumbered
    - VitaliĬ AmurskiĬ and VitaliĬ StatsinskiĬ, radio talk, 1999. (Tape 17)
    - Ziiaiushchie vysoty by Aleksandr Zinov'ev, read by Vl. Shtepa, undated. (Tape 17)
      The tape (on two cassettes) is unnumbered
    - Arkhipelag Gulag by Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn. Stage version developed and recorded by V. Sechin, 1980 August 17. (Tape 17)
    - General Aleksandr Lebed', regarding Pridnestrov'ie region and possible run for president. Conversation with Konstantin Zatulin, historian. Discussion regarding publication of books by AndreĬ SiniavskiĬ and IUliĬ Daniel' with a foreword by Veniamin Kaverin and Belaia kniga. Archbishop Juvenal, biography and conversation regarding hierarchs of the Russian Orthodox Church who served as KGB agents. IUriĬ Mitiunov, telephone conversation regarding AndreĬ BabitskiĬ, Mrs. Debrianskaia, Mark DeĬch, Vadim BelotserkovskiĬ, and Denis Pekarev; and Ginzburg's story about Vadim BelotserkovskiĬ. Radio Free Europe (RFE) broadcasts. News broadcast and Itogi —,; EvgeniĬ Kiselev Moscow television program., 1993 (Tape 17: 1)
      Use copy reference number: 2004c55_a_0001123
    - Crisis of power, Boris Yeltsin and Ruslan Khasbulatov, audio clips. Liliia Shevtsova and Viacheslav Nikonov discussion on political issues. German Solomatin regarding meetings of Boris Yeltsin in Karelia. EvgeniĬ Kiselev, talk regarding speech of Vladimir Isakov, deputy of the Supreme Soviet. SergeĬ Goriachev, report from Washington, D.C., about the public life of U.S. politicians and transfer of power in the United States. Staff meeting of Russian Federation radio and television personnel regarding minister of press and information EvgeniĬ Kiselev talk regarding television and politics. Commercials. News, ca 1993 (Tape 17: 2)
    - Aleksandr Ginzburg, telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov, ValeriĬ Seleznev, and other Moscow correspondents. News., probably 1990s (Tape 17: 3)
    - Radio Liberty news Radio programs with Petr Vail', Aleksandr Genis, SergeĬ Dovlatov, IUriĬ Afanas'ev, and Mikhail Bombin. News and radio programs with Mark DeĬch, AnatoliĬ Dotsenko, Margaret Thatcher, and Jeane Kirkpatrick., late 1980s (Tape 17: 4)
    - Vladimir Voinovich, interview by Arina Ginzburg for Voice of America. Alla Demidova, actress, on theatre, art, and herself (in French). Includes questions and answers session, 1987. (Tape 17: 5)
    - Maria Rozanova (Siniavski) and AndreĬ SiniavskiĬ regarding Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Eduard Limonov, Joseph Brodsky, and others, with introduction by Natal'ia Ivanova News., Late 1980s (Tape 17: 6)
    - IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow) regarding the Congress of People's Deputies. Archbishop Pavlo Vasylik regarding arrest of a Greek-Catholic priest. Pushkin square demonstration in Moscow. French policy towards foreign visitors and other issues. News., ca 1990 (Tape 17: 7)
    - IUriĬ Afanas'ev regarding history and its interpretation and other issues, ca 1990 (Tape 17: 8)
    - IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow) regarding the Congress of People's Deputies. News, ca 1990 (Tape 17: 9)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with DmitriĬ Borisov (Moscow). VitaliĬ Korotych about publication of Arkhipelag GULAG. Rusofobiia by Igor' Shafarevich. Ronald Reagan's visit to the Soviet Union. Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow). Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna. News., ca 1989-1990 (Tape 17: 10)
    - Discussion (probably at the editorial office of the Russkaia mysl' in Paris) regarding feminist movement in the USSR News, probably late 1980s (Tape 17: 11)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow). Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with unidentified person in St. Petersburg Ginzburg about a letter from a psychiatrist regarding treatment of N. I. Borodin and lies about Soviet health care system. News., ca 1989-1990 (Tape 17: 12)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with unidentified correspondent (Moscow) News broadcasts, late 1980s -1990s (Tape 17: 13)
    - Referendum magazine, pilot issue, late 1980s -1990 (Tape 17: 14)
    - ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow), review of Vybor magazine no. 3. News, late 1980s -1990s (Tape 17: 15)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with artist Slava Sysoev (Moscow). Aleksandr and Arina Ginzburg, talk to Aleksandr Podrabinek(?) about a meeting in the American embassy of George Shultz with Soviet dissidents (Gleb IAkunin, Aleksandr Ogorodnikov, Lev Timofeev, SergeĬ Grigoriants, SergeĬ Kovalev, Larisa Bogoraz, and others) News, 1988 (Tape 17: 16)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with Lev Timofeev (Moscow) regarding Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, trip of AndreĬ Sakharov to Armenia, and the Association of Repression Victims ValeriĬ Senderov regarding Azerbaijan intelligentsia in Karabakh and Sumgait regions, ca 1987-1988 (Tape 17: 17)
    - Democratic Union opposition party, political and economic conditions, and interethnic relations in the Soviet Union. News, ca 1988-1991 (Tape 17: 18)
    - Ginzburg and Professor Efim Etkind regarding Viktor Nekrasov obituary. Nathan Shcharansky, interview by Arina and Aleksandr Ginzburg, 1987 (Tape 17: 19)
    - Liudmila Belousova and Oleg Protopopov, interview by Ginzburg. News, ca 1988. (Tape 17: 20)
    - SergeĬ Kuznetsov regarding resolution against arrest of Alain Guillo (French journalist) in Afghanistan SergeĬ Kuznetsov, conversation with Ginzburg. News, 1988. (Tape 17: 21)
    - AnatoliĬ StrelianyĬ regarding life of Russian villages. RFE broadcasts. News, 1987 or 1988 (Tape 17: 22)
    - "International Seminar of Non-governmental Organizations on Human Rights," Baltic republics, and Memorial project. How to cooperate with authorities. Ginzburg (Paris), conversation with ValeriĬ Senderov and Vladimir KorsunskiĬ (Moscow) News, probably late 1980s or early 1990s (Tape 17: 23)
    - Moscow report on possible Jewish pogroms during celebration of the 1,000th anniversary of Christianity in Russia; interethnic conflicts. Short stories. News, ca 1988 (Tape 17: 24)
    - Radio (mostly Radio Liberty) broadcasts. News, ca 1988 (Tape 17: 25)
    - Not listed, ca 1988 (Tape 17: 26)
    - Radio Liberty broadcasts. News, ca 1988 (Tape 17: 27)
    - Ginzburg, conversation with unidentified American correspondent. ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow) regarding Russkaia mysl', Ukrainian Helsinki group, and Ukrainian, Armenian, and Russian emigration. News, late 1980s (Tape 17: 28)
    - Ignat Solzhenitsyn, interview by BBC, London, 22 January 1989 (Tape 17: 29)
    - Not listed (Tape 17: 30)
    - Not described. News, ca 1988 (Tape 17: 31)
    - IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow) regarding the Congress of People's Deputies, probably 1990 (Tape 17: 32)
    - Vladimir Voinovich, press conference. Hijacking of a Soviet airplane, press conference. News, 1988 (Tape 17: 33)
    - AndreĬ Sakharov, Elena Bonner, Mustafa Dzhemilev, statement at press conference regarding Crimean Tatars. Persecution of Mykola Rudenko in the Dnepropetrovsk psychiatric clinic, statement. News, 1987 or 1988 (Tape 17: 34)
    - Not listed (Tape 17: 35)
    - Poet Genrikh Sapgir, conversation (Paris) News, undated. (Tape 17: 36)
    - IUriĬ Orlov with his son Aleksandr Orlov, wife Irina Orlova, and Elena Bonner, press conference regarding Orlov's trial., ca 1986 (Tape 17: 37)
    - Pinkhas Podrabinek, statement about KGB offer to his son Aleksandr Podrabinek of avoiding criminal charges by leaving the Soviet Union with his father and brother Kirill. AndreĬ Sakharov regarding demonstration on the Constitution Day. Elena Bonner regarding alternative "respect your laws" demonstration. News, ca 1988 (Tape 17: 38)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), conversation with a Moscow correspondent regarding meeting of Mikhail Gorbachev with hierarchs of the Russian Orthodox Church. News, ca 1988 (Tape 18: 39)
    - AndreĬ Sakharov, press conference with question and answer session, 1987 or 1988 (Tape 18: 40)
    - Radio program about Boris Zelikson, SergeĬ Khakhaev, and ValeriĬ Ronkin, 1989 (Tape 18: 41)
    - Foster care system in France, discussion, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 42)
    - Artists in the Soviet Union, their living conditions, exhibits, relations with authorities. News, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 43)
    - Igor' Ogurtsov, regarding political resistance in the USSR, undated. (Tape 18: 44)
      In Russian, with German translation
    - Clergy in the Soviet Union and relations between the Russian Orthodox Church and the authorities, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 45)
    - Not listed (Tape 18: 46)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow) Ginzburg and IUriĬ Mitiunov regarding censorship over Radio Liberty. News from Russia, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 47)
    - Ginzburg (Paris) with Vladimir Riabokon' and ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow), telephone conversation regarding political and cultural life in the Soviet Union. IUriĬ Mitiunov with AndreĬ Sakharov, SergeĬ Stankevich, and others regarding SergeĬ Kuznetsov and meetings in Moscow. News from Russia, 1989 (Tape 18: 48)
    - IUriĬ Mitiunov regarding Literaturnaia gazeta. Priest GeorgiĬ Edel'shteĬn regarding ecumenical conference in Zagorsk on 10-14 May 1982. Former political prisoner talks to Ginzburg about his imprisonment and fellow prisoners. News from Russia, ca 1988 (Tape 18: 49)
    - Ginzburg (Paris) and IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow), telephone discussion regarding meetings in Moscow, Abkhazia, and other places. News, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 50)
    - Natan E'del'man, historian, question and answer session. Ginzburg, conversation with writer Viktor Suvorov, ca 2000 (Tape 18: 51)
    - Ginzburg receives phone messages from Moscow. IUriĬ Liubimov, interview by Arina Ginzburg, 1988 (Tape 18: 52)
    - IUriĬ Afanas'ev, speech., ca 1988 (Tape 18: 53)
      In Russian, with French translation
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow), ca 1988 (Tape 18: 54)
    - IUriĬ Afanas'ev, question and answer session. VitaliĬ Urazhtsev, NikolaĬ Moskovchenko, Tigran Aslamazian, discussions., ca 1988 (Tape 18: 55)
    - Andreev, IUli?Ĭ Kim, NikolaĬ Rozov, Khromov, AlekseĬ Gladkov, Mikhail Lemeshev, DmitriĬ Vasil'ev, discussion regarding the Pamiat' society meeting in Moscow on 21 May 1986, ca 1988 (Tape 18: 56)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow), ca 1988 (Tape 18: 57)
    - Ginzburg receives phone messages from Moscow, 1988 (Tape 18: 58)
    - Ginzburg receives phone messages from Moscow. Establishment of the Democratic Union (DemokraticheskiĬ soiuz) Restoration of the Greek Catholic Church in Ukraine Amendments to the law on freedom of faith Political prisoners in the Soviet camps during perestroĬka, 1988 (Tape 18: 59)
    - Duplicate of tape #52 (Tape 18: 60)
    - Ginzburg receives phone messages from Moscow, 1988 (Tape 18: 61)
    - Arina Ginzburg for Voice of America. Olga Borodinets (Borodina?), Galina Cheplinskaia, and Igor' Tsar'kov regarding meeting in Moscow on 30 October 1988. Ginzburg receives phone messages from Moscow. (Tape 18: 62)
    - Semen Gluzman and Anatoly Koryagin, statement regarding criminal psychiatry, ca 1988 (Tape 18: 63)
    - Samoilova, V., court trial, undated (Tape 18: 64)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with SergeĬ Grigoriants and ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow), ca 1988 (Tape 18: 65)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov and ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow), ca 1988 (Tape 18: 66)
    - Essays for the Russkaia mysl' newspaper. Irina IlovaĬskaia-Alberti and Naum Korzhavin, ca 1988 (Tape 18: 67)
    - Phone messages from Moscow for Semen MirskiĬ (Radio Liberty Paris Bureau), ca 1988 (Tape 18: 68)
    - Appeal in defense of Aleksandr Podrabinek transmitted to Aleksandr Ginzburg from New York. Memorial service for Petr Grigorenko in New York., 1987 (Tape 18: 69)
    - Egor Ligachev regarding his trip to attend the French Communist Party Congress, late 1980s (Tape 18: 70)
    - Reports, poems, songs, undated (Tape 18: 71)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow), Late 1980s (Tape 18: 72)
      Inscription on the tape does not match the content
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov, ValeriĬ Senderov, and SergeĬ Grigoriants (Moscow). AndreĬ Sakharov regarding his trip to Sverdlovsk. Elena Bonner, report, 1989 (Tape 18: 73)
    - Ginzburg and Leonid Vladimirov, BBC radio program, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 74)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversations with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow) and others, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 75-77)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov, ValeriĬ Senderov, and SergeĬ Grigoriants (Moscow). Information from Moscow for Arina Ginzburg, ca 1989 (Tape 18: 78)
    - Arina Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with Lev Timofeev (Moscow), ca 1989 (Tape 18: 79)
    - ValeriĬ Senderov, Tamara Grigoriants, and IUriĬ Mitiunov. Speech and press conference of AndreĬ Sakharov in London for the Radio Liberty Russian Service. Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow), ca 1989 (Tape 18: 80)
    - Ginzburg at Ekho Moskvy (Moscow echo) radio program, ca 1990s (Tape 18: 81)
    - Ginzburg, Maria Rozanova (Siniavski), Aleksandr Glotser, and others, press conference on Soviet archives with KGB personnel, ca 1990s (Tape 18: 82)
    - Ginzburg and Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna, discussion on cancellation by Moscow television of the Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn program;. Press release by Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna, c1995 (Tape 18: 83)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with Lev AleĬnik (Moscow). Two protest meetings in Moscow., 1990s (Tape 18: 84)
    - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, at the Ostankino TV station, Moscow, 12 September 1994 (Tape 18: 85)
    - Maria Rozanova (Siniavski) about Sintaksis magazine. Press conference on financial and economics of the Russian Federation, 1990s (Tape 18: 86)
    - IAsin, EvgeniĬ (minister of economics of the Russian Federation), press conference in Paris. News on Russian public television., 1990s (Tape 18: 87)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversations with ValeriĬ Senderov (Moscow), and Kartashov (Munich). Information about the Soviet Union, 1990s (Tape 18: 88)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with VasiliĬ Aksenov (New York) regarding Aleksandr Glezer's press conference. information from IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow), ca 1990 (Tape 18: 89)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with Vladimir KorsunskiĬ (Moscow)., ca 1990 (Tape 18: 90)
      Includes Radio Liberty program about Aleksandr Glezer
    - Symposium on literature, 1990s (Tape 19: 91)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow). Discussion on literature, 1990s (Tape 19: 92)
    - Aleksandr Glezer, press conference in Paris regarding his visit to the Soviet Union, with NikolaĬ TeliakovskiĬ, IUriĬ Mamleev, and Genrikh Sapgir, January 1990 (Tape 19: 93)
    - Aleksandr Glezer, interview by Ginzburg. Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with IUriĬ Mitiunov (Moscow), 1989 (Tape 19: 94)
    - Ginzburg (Paris), telephone conversation with Vladimir KorsunskiĬ (Moscow). Aleksandr Glezer's statement in Moscow. AnatoliĬ Sobchak, interview by IUriĬ Mitiunov Aleksandr Ginzburg, lecture with question and answer session, October 1987 (Tape 19: 95)
    - Aleksandr Glezer, press conference. Jiovanni Bensi regarding polemics between Adam Michnik and Lech Wałęsa, late 1989-1990 (Tape 19: 96)
    - VitaliĬ AmurskiĬ, V poiskakh odnoi assotsiatsii. Radio presentation of Georges Nivat: Rene Guerra, IUriĬ Kuper, Vladimir Maksimov, interview, 21 January 1989. Benedikt Sarnov, interview by VitaliĬ AmurskiĬ in memory of Osip Mandel'shtam, 22-23 December 1988, 1988-1989 (Tape 19: 97)
    - Ginzburg regarding Viktor Sipiatkus, undated (Tape 19: 98)
    - Ginzburg regarding article in Moskovskie novosti newspaper, ca 1990s (Tape 19: 99)
    - Ginzburg interview at the "Samizdat — al'ternativnaia kul'tura s 60kh po 80e gody v Tsentral'noi i Vostochnoi Evrope" exhibit, Berlin, 25 September 2000 (Tape 19: 100)
    - Ginzburg, interview by Nemetskaia volna, undated (Tape 19: 101)
    - Ginzburg regarding his dismissal from Russkaia mysl', undated, ca 1997 (Tape 19: 102)
    - Natal'ia Solzhenitsyna, press conference regarding third court trial of Aleksandr Ginzburg, 11 July 1978 (Tape 19: 103)
    - Truth about the Solzhenitsyn Fund, press conference, Zurich, 19 September 1978. (Tape 19: 104)
      Includes Kronid LiubarskiĬ speech
    - Radio Liberty Paris Bureau broadcasts, 6-7 May 1979 (Tape 19: 105)
    - Ginzburg, speech on human rights in the Soviet Union, 12 November 1979. (Tape 19: 106)
      Two cassettes
    - McGoff lecture series: Aleksandr Ginzburg, Public lecture, 16 April 1980. Two cassettes First classroom visit, 17 April 1980 Press conference, University of California, 17 April 1980 West Hall luncheon, 18 April 1980 Student roundtable discussion, 18 April 1980 Second classroom visit, 18 April 1980 Social hour and dinner, 18 April 1980 3 side series, side 3 is not in the Hoover Archives, 16-18 April 1980. (Tape 19: 107)
      Use copy reference number: 2004c55_a_0001124
      Eight cassettes
    - Radio Liberty, discussion regarding exchange of Soviet political prisoners for two Soviet spies, 29-30 April 1980 (Tape 19: 108)
    - Four Soviet political prisoners, press conference, New York, 30 April 1980 (Tape 19: 109)
    - Dokumenty i liudi, in memory of IUriĬ Galanskov, Radio Free Europe program with Ginzburg's comments, 6-7 November 1982 (Tape 18: 110)
    - Forum, Voice of America program honoring the Moscow Helsinki Group, 1985. (Tape 18: 111)
      With Aleksandr Ginzburg, Elena Bonner, Liudmila Alekseeva, Nina Strokata, Aishe Seitmuratova
    - AndreĬ Sakharov, press conference, 14 January 1988. (Tape 18: 112)
      Comments by Elena Bonner and Aleksandr and Kirill Podrabinek
    - Arina Ginzburg and Alla Latynina, interview, 30 January 1990 (Tape 18: 113)
    - Ginzburg and Irina IlovaĬskaia-Alberti regarding changes in Russkaia mysl', Radio France (International program), 3 November 1997 (Tape 18: 114)
    - Ginzburg and Irina IlovaĬskaia-Alberti, Radio France (International program), 3 November 1997 (Tape 18: 115)
      poor quality
    - Ginzburg and Elena Bonner, conversation, 12 November 1997 (Tape 19: 116)
    - Ginzburg, interview by A. Chukoev, Express khronika, no.16 (37), 2 December 1997 (Tape 19: 117)
    - Ginzburg, Golos truda program, Radio Liberty, 12 December 1997. (Tape 19: 118)
    - Ginzburg, interview by Frantsiia segodnia radio program, 19 August 1998 (Tape 19: 119)
    - Ginzburg, interview by Radio Free Europe, 5 September 1998 (Tape 19: 120)
    - Ginzburg, interview in honor of the 80th birthday of Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Radio France (International program), 12 December 1998 (Tape 19: 121)
    - Fatima Salkazanova, interview by Radio France (International program), May 1999 (Tape 19: 122)
    - RossiĬskie pravozashchitniki o yugoslavskoĬ tragedii, Radio Liberty, 13 April 1999 (Tape 19: 123)
    - Chto proizoshlo s 'RusskoĬ mysl'iu?' interview of Irina Krivova, chief editor of the Russkaia mysl' Paris bureau, 23 December 2000 (Tape 19: 124)
  - Sound recordings, 1970s-1990s. (Box 20-26)
    Includes 299 compact sound cassettes, with Soviet underground poetry and poetic and protest songs
    - Agafonov, Gleb. 16 compact sound cassettes AleshkovskiĬ, IUz. 2 compact sound cassettes Almazov Boris. 1 compact sound cassette Andreeva, Anna, reading poetry by Daniil Andreev. 1 compact sound cassette Bachurin, EvgeniĬ. 10 compact sound cassettes Bachurin, EvgeniĬ, interview. 1 compact sound cassette Baez, Joan. 2 compact sound cassettes Brodsky, Joseph. 10 compact sound cassettes (Box 20)